VICTORIA: Jamie!
CLENT: He took just forty five seconds to propose ionisation. No prior knowledge.
他仅仅用了45秒就提出了离子化的建议, 没有任何背景了解。
ARDEN: Well, it took us and the Academy of Scientists years.
啊, 当初可花了我们科学院好几年的时间。
GARRETT: The computer took three milliseconds.
电脑用了三毫秒
ARDEN: Yes, well, we had to programme it first.
是的, 但我们需要先编程
CLENT: Quite. Well, before I make a final decision, I want the computer's assessment on this Doctor.
的确是。在我作最后决定之前, 我想让电脑对博士做一个评估。
GARRETT: We must be absolutely sure.
这事我们绝对不能搞错
CLENT: State the work potential and community value of the Doctor.
请评估博士的工作潜力和社区价值
COMPUTER: More information is necessary for a full evaluation. High IQ but undisciplined for our needs.
需要更多信息才能做出完整的评估。智商很高, 但不守纪律, 所以不满足我们的需要。
Present evaluation, to be used on research projects, but could be obstructive in certain situations.
当前评估：可用于研究项目,但在特定场景下可能造成阻碍
DOCTOR: Oh, there you are.
哦, 你在这儿啊
CLENT: Doctor, would you mind
博士, 你介意吗
DOCTOR: I've been looking everywhere. Why don't you label your doors?
我到处找了个遍, 你们为什么不在门上贴标识呢
CLENT: Yes, this is a private meeting.
是的, 这是一个内部会议
DOCTOR: Yes, I realise that, and I'm sorry.
哦, 我意识到了, 不好意思
CLENT: And we have not yet completed our business.
我们还没有完成我们的工作
DOCTOR: Look, I wouldn't intrude if I didn't think it necessary. What I have to say is extremely important. After all, you did ask me to help you, didn't you?
你看, 如果我觉得没这个必要的话我是不会干涉的。但我要说的非常重要。毕竟, 你的确说过让我帮助你们, 说过吧？
ARDEN: Has something happened to the warrior?
勇士那边发生了什么吗？
DOCTOR: Well, it has something to do with that, yes.
嗯, 跟那个相关, 是的
CLENT: We have more serious matters on hand.
我们手头有更正经的事情
DOCTOR: This is serious!
这事很正经！
ARDEN: Now let him tell us, Clent. Well?
让他说吧, Clent, 怎样?
DOCTOR: Thank you. It's the, it's the helmet. It's not what we thought it was.
谢谢你。就是, 就是那个头盔, 并不是我们之前想的那样
CLENT: It's a prehistoric drinking cup.
那就是个史前的饮水杯子
DOCTOR: No! It has electronic connections.
不！上面有电子链接
CLENT: E? What are you talking about?
呃？你在说些什么啊？
ARDEN: But that's impossible. You must be mistaken.
那是不可能的, 你一定搞错了
DOCTOR: No, I'm positive. You realise what this means?
不, 我很确定。你知道这意味着什么吗？
ARDEN: Well it must mean the civilisation he came from must be more advanced than we thought.
这肯定意味着他来自一个先进的文明, 比我们之前想的要先进得多
DOCTOR: Yes, indeed. They even had astronauts, it appears.
是的, 的确。看起来他们甚至有宇航员
CLENT: How do you mean?
这什么意思？
DOCTOR: This headpiece is no warriors tin-hat. It's a highly sophisticated space helmet!
这个头套可不是勇士的帽子, 它是一个非常复杂的宇航头盔！
CLENT: Aren't you jumping to conclusions, Doctor, for a scientist?
你这太跳跃了吧？博士, 作为一个科学家...
ARDEN: But if this is true?
但如果这是真的呢？
DOCTOR: If this is true your project is in danger.
如果这是真的, 你们的项目就危险了
CLENT: In what way? How can one preserved body, however old, effect us?
怎么说？一具这么古老的尸体, 怎么能影响我们？
DOCTOR: How did he get here? Well, he didn't walk, did he?
他怎么到这里来的？你看, 他不是走来的, 对吧？
CLENT: Well, if what you say is true, by spaceship.
好, 如果你说的是对的, 是坐飞船来的。
DOCTOR: Yes, and where is that spaceship now?
是的, 飞船现在在什么地方？
ARDEN: In the glacier. Then it must still be intact. He had no signs of mutilation. He couldn't have crashed. He must of landed. Clent, can't you see the importance of such a discovery?
在冰川里面。估计还是完整的。他的身体没有损坏的痕迹, 所以不应该是坠毁的, 而是正常着陆的。Clent, 你看出来没, 我们有了个重大发现？
CLENT: The propulsion unit of the spacecraft is probably
飞船的推进装置很可能是...
GARRETT: Probably atomic powered.
很可能是靠原子能驱动的
CLENT: Quite. And, er, if we use the ioniser at full power
很可能。如果我们把离子器功率开到最大
DOCTOR: This reactor pile could be exploded or be activated.
反应堆就可能爆炸, 至少也是激活了
CLENT: But if we don't
但如果我们没有...
GARRETT: The whole area will be contaminated.
这整个地方都将会被污染
CLENT: But if we don't use the ioniser, what then? We are part of a world plan. Now, if we hold back that plan cannot go into operation.
但如果我们不用离子器, 又会怎样？我们是现在是世界级计划的一部分, 如果我们按兵不动整个计划就无法继续了
GARRETT: We could hold it at minimal power.
我们可以用最小动力
CLENT: Not good enough.
这个方法不够好
ARDEN: No, we daren't take the risk. The contamination level would last for five decades or more.
不, 我们承担不了这个风险。核污染可能会影响50年以上
CLENT: It merely makes the fine control of the heat level even more vital.
只不过需要需要精心控制好热度, 不超过危险阈值就是了(FIXME)
DOCTOR: Yes, well, I thought you ought to know.
是的, 我想你们也应该知道
CLENT: Yes, you were right, thank you. I must inform the computer immediately for its decision.
是的, 你是对的, 谢谢你。我得立即找电脑询问该做怎样的决定
ARDEN: Well, we shall need more facts.
不过, 我们应该有更多的证据
CLENT: Well, furnish me with facts then!
那就赶紧去找啊!
JAMIE: Doctor!
博士
DOCTOR: Jamie!
JAMIE: The warrior's come alive!
勇士复活了！
ARDEN: Alive?
复活了？
CLENT, DOCTOR + GARRETT: What?
什么？
JAMIE: He's taken Victoria. I couldn't stop him!
他抓走了Victoria, 我没能拦住！
ARDEN: Alive. and I found it.
活的, 我找到的
CLENT: Alive?
活了？
DOCTOR: Strange.
奇怪
CLENT: How did it happen?
怎么发生的？
JAMIE: Well, we were just talking, and I turned, and there he was standing right next to us.
就是, 我们那时正在说话, 一转头, 他就正站在我们旁边
ARDEN: That's impossible. To be preserved, yes, but to come alive? Impossible.
那不可能。尸身保持完整, 这可能。但复活？不可能
DOCTOR: For a human being, maybe.
从人类的角度来看, 也许不可能
ARDEN: What, not human?
什么？不是人类
DOCTOR: Look at this table.
看看这个桌子
CLENT: Well, it's been burned.
哦, 有烧焦的痕迹
ARDEN: Well, I used a low voltage especially.
我特意用了低电压
DOCTOR: Yes, but a high current.
是的, 但电流很大
ARDEN: Yes but it was quite safe.
是, 但这样是安全的
DOCTOR: But if that current passed through a low resistance.
但如果这个电流通过的低阻抗电路...
GARRETT: Extremely high temperatures.
就会产生高温
CLENT: The intense heat must have shocked him back into life.
这强热就可能把他激活
JAMIE: Oh look, I don't know what you're all talking about, but all I know is Victoria's in danger and what are we doing to save her?
哦, 你看, 我不知道你们在说些什么, 但我知道的是 Victoria 现在很危险, 我们得做点什么赶紧救她
DOCTOR: Yes Jamie, you're right. Come on. She can't have gone far.
是的Jamie, 你说的对。来吧, 她不可能走太远
JAMIE: Well, come on then.
好, 来
CLENT: Danger red alert, danger red alert. Intruders within perimeter. Capture and control. Priority one. Repeat to all posts.
危险, 红色警报。危险, 红色警报。防线内发现闯入者, 请抓捕并控制住。最高优先级, 请向各站重复播报。
JAMIE: But within a perimeter? But supposing they're way out of it?
防线内？应该已经走远了吧？
ANNOUNCER: Danger red alert, danger red alert. Intruders within perimeter. Capture and control. Priority one.
危险, 红色警报。危险, 红色警报。防线内发现闯入者, 请抓捕并控制住。最高优先级。
CLENT: Well, that'll be just too bad. Obviously I can't release men for an extensive search outside the base.
哦, 那就太糟了。显然我不能把人派到基地外去展开搜索工作
DOCTOR: But she may be in danger of her life! You can't take that decision!
但她可能有生命危险, 你不能这样决定！
CLENT: Very well. You want an impartial opinion? I shall ask the computer.
好吧, 你想要一个公正的决定是吗？我问问电脑吧
JAMIE: Oh, not the computer.
哦, 又是电脑
DOCTOR: It's a waste of time asking the computer.
问电脑就是浪费时间
VICTORIA: Who are you?
你是谁？
VARGA: (hissing) Varga.
VICTORIA: Where are you from?
你从哪儿来？
VARGA: From the Red Planet.
来自红色星球
VICTORIA: Mars? We thought you were dead and then you came alive. What happened?
火星？我们以为你已经死了, 但你又复活了, 怎么回事？
VARGA: Too many questions.
你问题太多了
VICTORIA: I'm curious, that's all.
我很好奇, 仅此而已
VARGA: I need answers from you.
我需要从你这里达到一些答案
VICTORIA: I don't think I can help you very much.
我不觉得我可以帮到你什么
VARGA: Answers.
答案
VICTORIA: Is that a gun?
那是一把枪吗？
VARGA: How long was I in the ice?
我在冰里面呆了多久？
VICTORIA: I don't know, I. One of the scientists said you must have been there since the first ice age. Thousands of years ago.
我不知道。其中一个科学家说你们可能自从第一次冰川时期就在那里了, 几千年前
VARGA: That cannot be true.
那不可能
VICTORIA: Were there others with you?
有其他同伴跟你一起吗？
VARGA: Yes. Our spaceship crashed at the foot of the ice mountain. As we came out to investigate, a great avalanche of snow buried us.
是的, 我们飞船在冰山的脚下坠毁了。我们出来检查的时候, 巨大的雪崩淹没了我们
VICTORIA: Then the others are still trapped in the glacier, then.
那其他人现在还被困在冰川里
VARGA: I will free them. Then we will return to the Red Planet.
我要把他们救出来, 然后我们将返回红色星球
VICTORIA: How? You can't get them out by yourself.
怎么救？仅靠你自己没法把他们弄出来
VARGA: You will help. How was I brought to life?
你也要帮忙。我是怎么复活的？
VICTORIA: Let the scientists here on Earth help you.
让这里地球上的科学家帮你吧
VARGA: Tell me! They would not help me. They would keep me as a curiosity, and they would leave my warriors for dead, or destroy them.
告诉我！他们不会帮助我, 他们只会把我当做稀奇玩意儿困住, 然后不管我的勇士们死活, 甚至可能毁掉他们
VICTORIA: No. No, they, they wouldn't.
不, 不, 他们, 他们不会的
VARGA: But with my men, I can talk from strength. Then we shall decide.
但有了我的人, 我能说服他们团结起来, 然后就可以做出决定
VICTORIA: Decide? Decide what?
决定? 决定什么？
VARGA: Whether to go back to our own world, or to conquer this.
我们是回到我们自己的世界, 还是征服现在这个
CLENT: All relevant factors now presented. How should we act?
所有相关因素都在这里了, 我们应该怎么应对？
JAMIE: Och, how's a machine to know?
嗷, 一台机器怎么能知道？
DOCTOR: Come on, Jamie, have patience. Give it a chance.
得了, Jamie, 有点耐心, 给它个机会
COMPUTER: Ionisation programme should continue as planned. A limited number of lives are expected to be lost.
离子化程序应该按原计划继续。估计可能会损失有限数量的生命
JAMIE: What about Victoria, though?
Victoria 会怎么样呢, 嗯？
DOCTOR: Shush, Jamie.
嘘, Jamie
COMPUTER: However, the suspected presence of an alien spacecraft must be investigated, in case of potentially fissionable material.
不过, 外星飞船的状态比较可疑, 应该进行调查, 以防有可分裂物质出现
JAMIE: Spacecraft! Hey, do you reckon that's where the warrior's gone back to?
飞船! 嘿, 你觉得这个勇士回到哪里去了？
DOCTOR: Well, he didn't come by Shetland Pony, Jamie.
喔, 他可不是骑雪德兰矮种马来的, Jamie
COMPUTER: In order to accommodate this priority the workload has been rescheduled to free one scientist investigator.
为了应对这项优先工作, 工作量分配情况已经进行了调整, 可释放一位科学家展开调查
CLENT: Who should be released?
该释放谁去呢？
COMPUTER: Scientist Arden.
科学家 Arden
CLENT: Well, Arden, do you think you could handle this ice giant single-handed?
哦, Arden, 你觉得自己一个人可以应对寒冰巨人吗？
ARDEN: Well, I shall need at least one guard.
嗯, 我还至少需要一个卫兵
JAMIE: Well, what about me then? I could go with him.
那我怎么样？ 我跟他去
DOCTOR: Yes, he's a capable lad.
是的, 这是个能力不错的小伙子
CLENT: Well, the computer said one investigator only.
但是电脑说只需要派一个人去
DOCTOR: That was from your staff, Jamie's extra.
那是你那边的人力, Jamie算额外的
JAMIE: Aye.
是啊
GARRETT: The mission must be carried out. The computer has ordered it.
这项任务必须开始了, 电脑已经下了指令了
CLENT: As the Doctor has agreed to help us with the ioniser. Yes, very well, the boy can go.
博士答应了帮助我们弄那个离子器。好吧, 这小伙子可以去
DOCTOR: Oh good.
好
CLENT: But you must leave immediately, because the sooner we know whether there is a reactor buried inside that glacier or not, the better.
你们得立即出发, 因为越早了解到情况越好, 到底是不是在冰川里面是否埋着一个反应堆
JAMIE: Aye, maybe, but Victoria's important too, you know.
是啊, 有可能。但Victoria也很重要, 你知道的
CLENT: You don't seem to realise, boy, the fate of the world could be at stake. The girl must take her chance.
你看来还没有明白, 孩子, 这世界的命运已经危在旦夕了。那个女孩就看她自己的造化了
STORR: What ye trying to do? Cripple me?
你打算做什么？弄残我？
PENLEY: You know the trouble with you. Storr? You're just stupid.
你知道自己惹上什么麻烦了吗？你可真蠢
STORR: How was I to know it would get infected?
我怎么知道可能会受到感染？
PENLEY: If you'd listened to me in the first place.
如果你一开始就听我的
STORR: Aye, you'd have stuffed me to the eyeballs with anti-this and anti-that. I'd have been flat on my back for weeks.
是啊, 你一直在我眼前晃, 反对这个, 反对那个。我都躺了好几个星期了
PENLEY: Where as now, you're fighting fit.
就目前而言, 你恢复得还可以
STORR: Ach, well, someone has to do things.
啊, 某人有事情做了
PENLEY: Mmm. Well, that someone isn't going to be you.
唔, 那个某人应该不是你
STORR: Ach, it's nothing. I'll pull through.
啊, 没事, 我能撑过去
PENLEY: Yes, I'm rather afraid you will. But if you don't do what I say you'll soon be in a coma, which at least would give me a bit of peace.
是的, 我觉得你会的。但如果你不按我说的去做, 你很快就会陷入昏迷, 倒可以让我安静一会儿
STORR: Don't try scare me with all that scientific guff.
别拿那些科学的东西来吓唬我
PENLEY: I'm just telling you, Storr. You got a headache?
我正跟你说呢。你头疼吗？
STORR: Ach, it's nothing.
啊, 没什么
PENLEY: What I like about you is if a polar bear got you you'd give him indigestion. Feeling fuzzy in the head, eh?
我喜欢你的是, 就算一头北极熊也会拿你没办法(FIXME)。觉得有点头晕不？
STORR: I will not let it beat me. Is it going to be bad?
我不会让它打跨我。将会很糟糕吗？
PENLEY: You won't know much about it.
你不会知道得太多的
STORR: My mouth's dry.
我的嘴比较干
PENLEY: Here's a what do you call it? A tomato. It's nearly ripe.
这里有一个...你们叫它什么来着？西红柿。基本上是熟的
STORR: Ach, you shouldnae have done that. I've been waiting weeks for that to ripen properly.
啊, 早就该这样了。我等了好几个星期等它成熟
PENLEY: Take it, it'll do you good.
吃了吧, 对你有好处
STORR: Ach.
啊
PENLEY: Well, there are advantages to living in a plant museum, even this close to the glacier.
嗯, 住在一个行星博物馆还是有好处的, 虽然离冰川太近了点
STORR: Ah, so even a scientist can appreciate it then?
哈, 一个科学及也懂得欣赏这个了？
PENLEY: Well, there's warmth and food. Selected ancient food plants. Tomatoes, carrots, potatoes, strawberries. A world out of Atlantis.
是啊, 又有热气又有食物, 很好的传统作物：西红柿, 胡萝卜, 土豆, 草莓。传说中的亚特兰蒂斯啊 (FIXME)
STORR: Aye, helps me picture how it was before they killed off all the plants. There was spring then, and flowers.
是啊, 帮我回忆一下他们杀死这些植物之前是怎样的。那时有春天, 还有花。
You could pick the fruit off the trees. Now you rotten scientists (coughs) drop down dead.
你能从树上摘水果。但现在你们这些烂科学家就... (FIXME)
PENLEY: Even so it's not the nicest way to live.
即便如此还是不太适合居住
STORR: Aye.
是啊
PENLEY: An avalanche waiting on your doorstep.
感觉雪崩马上就要来了
STORR: Not leaving here until I have to.
不到万不得已不离开这里
PENLEY: Granted.
当然
STORR: You're not going out after food, are you? You wouldn't know what to do without me. Where are you going, anyway?
你不是出去找食物吧, 是吗？没我的话你不知道怎么办的。你要去哪儿？
PENLEY: Well I've learnt enough from you to take care of myself, and it's for your idiotic sake that I'm going.
我已经学了不少了, 足够自己照顾自己。我是去给你个蠢人弄点东西
STORR: Where to?
去哪儿？
PENLEY: The base.
基地
STORR: You're going to hand me in to rehabilitation. Africa. Never trust anybody.
你是打算把我交过去, 送我去非洲聚居地。非洲。不能相信任何人啊
PENLEY: I'm going for drugs. And if I don't get them, you're as good as dead.
我只是去弄点药。如果我不弄来, 你就死翘翘了。
VICTORIA: It's, it's, it's, it's a
是。。。是。。。是一个。。。
VARGA: Go on.
继续
VICTORIA: It's a black box with wires. They connected it to you, and you came alive. I, well, I don't know how!
是一个黑色的盒子, 带电线的。他们把它连到你身上, 你就复活了。我, 我不懂怎么弄的！
VARGA: A power source. Resistance. A great heat and then life. This room we came from. We will go back to it.
一个电源。电阻。强热, 复活。我们来的房间, 我们要回去那里
VICTORIA: I'll tell you how to get there.
我可以告诉你怎么去那儿
VARGA: You will take me there. Without that power unit, my warriors are lifeless.
你将带我去那里, 没有能量设备的话, 我的勇士们就是死的
VICTORIA: But we have to go down the corridors. Supposing someone sees you?
但我们必须沿走廊过去, 假如有人看到你怎么办？
VARGA: I shall kill them. And you.
我会杀死他们, 还有你
VICTORIA: Me?
我？
VARGA: If you call for help.
如果你呼救的话。
VICTORIA: What is that?
那是什么？
VARGA: Sonic gun. It will burst your brain with noise.
音速枪。它会用噪音爆掉你的脑袋
JAMIE: There's no one been here. There's not a mark.
这里没有人, 一点痕迹也没有
ARDEN: Well, we didn't pass them on the way. Now, stand aside lad, will you?
我们在路上也没有碰到过。现在, 站一边去好吗, 小伙子
JAMIE: We were wrong, then. He's lost out there somewhere, Victoria with him.
我们搞错了, 他肯定在哪里迷路了, 带着 victoria
ARDEN: I can't get a reading. There's something inside there, but all it's doing is creating havoc with this radiation sensor.
没有任何读数, 这里面有什么东西在干扰辐射检测仪。
Arden calling Leader Clent. Arden calling Leader Clent, answer please.
Arden呼叫队长, Arden呼叫队长, 请回答
CLENT: Clent here. Report.
我是Clent, 报告情况吧
ARDEN: There's no sign of the fugitive or the girl. They didn't, couldn't have come this way.
没有逃犯和那个女孩的痕迹。他们没有走到这边来, 不可能的
CLENT: That was not the purpose of your mission. Please report correctly.
那不是你们任务的目的, 请按任务报告情况
ARDEN: No reading obtainable. The sensor is being jammed by some sort of a screening device. I can't make head nor tail of it.
没有获得任何读数, 检测仪被某种屏蔽设备干扰了。我没法走到干扰范围外
CLENT: But something is in there.
那里肯定有什么东西
ARDEN: Correct.
是的
CLENT: Well, come on then, man! Don't waste time. Go in and find out what it is!
那就这样吧, 别浪费时间, 进去把它找出来！
ARDEN: Well, not with the equipment I have with me now.
带着这些设备没法进去
CLENT: Very well then, return at once. The mission will be repeated with the correct equipment.
那, 马上回来。带上合适的设备, 继续你们的任务
ARDEN: But this is the proper equipment for the job.
但这就是合适的设备
CLENT: Obviously not. Don't waste time. Return immediately. Out.
显然不是, 别浪费时间, 马上回来。挂了
JAMIE: A nice boss you've got there.
你有个不错的老板
ARDEN: Yes. The trouble with Clent is that he's not a proper scientist, he's an organiser. He should've been born a robot.
Clent的麻烦是他不是一个科学家, 他是个管理者。他可能生下来就是个机器人
JAMIE: Let's go on.
我们继续吧
VICTORIA: No, no, it's not in there. It's further down the corridor.
不, 不, 不在那儿, 在通道的那一头
VARGA: The black box. Find it, quickly.
黑色匣子, 找到它, 快
GARRETT: It's still on half power, but it's holding well.
只开到一半功率, 但效果还可以
CLENT: Good...Well?
好...怎样?
DOCTOR: Well, I still think you ought to get in an expert. Why can't you get one?
我还是觉得你应该找个专家来, 为什么找不到呢？
CLENT: I choose not to.
我选择了不要
DOCTOR: But why?
为什么？
CLENT: You're not here to question me.
你在这里不是为了质问我的
DOCTOR: No, I'm here to help you, if I choose.
不是, 我在这里是为了帮你, 我选择的
CLENT: This is the most important job I've ever had. Now, every other project I've handled with ease. Nothing has failed.
这是我经历过的最重要的任务。我经手过的其它项目都很容易, 没有任何失败。之所以选我来, 就是我从来没有失败过。
I was chosen because I never fail. When I handpicked the team, I made one vital mistake.
但我在挑选团队成员的时候, 我犯了一个重大的错误
DOCTOR: This chap Penley.
Penley那个家伙
CLENT: Best man in Europe for ionisation studies. As it turned out, hopelessly temperamental.
欧洲离子化研究的第一人。但到头来, 很情绪化, 让人失望
DOCTOR: Temperamental or individual? Creative scientists have to be allowed some head you know.
情绪化还是有个性？对有创造力的科学家得宽容一点, 是吧
CLENT: Creative? Poppycock. When he walked out of here he proclaimed himself to be criminally, criminally irresponsible.
有创造力？胡说, 他从这里走出去的时候他就宣称他不再承担任何责任(FIXME)
DOCTOR: It couldn't have been just a simple gesture of protest?
可能只是简单地表示抗议吧？
CLENT: He was always protesting. This is a team, a team with a mission. If we fail, others cannot succeed.
他总是在抗议。这是一个团队, 有任务目标的团队。如果我们失败, 其它人也不能成功
DOCTOR: And your name will suffer. That's important.
然后你的名声就坏了, 这很重要
CLENT: I lead the team. I depend on the experts I picked. My judgement was sound. Others won't see it that way.
我带领这个团队, 我依赖于这些我挑出来的专家, 我相信我的判断。其他人可能不会这样看
DOCTOR: So you do need Penley.
所以你需要 Penley
CLENT: No, I do not need Penley. But I do need an equivalent brain. But it would be months before anyone else could pick up the knowledge that Penley acquired here.
不, 我不需要 Penley, 但我需要一个与他相当的大脑。不过仅仅是捡起Penley在这里了解到的那些情况就需要好几个月
Just isn't time, that's the pertinent issue.
现在不是时候, 这是最要命的问题
DOCTOR: Well, I'll try and help you, but I do think you might try trusting human beings instead of computers.
这样, 我会尽量帮你。但我真的觉得你应该试着相信这些人, 而不是电脑
CLENT: I trust no one, Doctor. Not any more. Human emotions are unreliable.
我谁也不信, 博士。不再信了。人的情感太不可靠的了。
I'll just go and see that the working area reserved for you in the Medi-Control Centre is ready.
我现在去看看媒体控制中心那边给你准备的工作区是否准备好了
VARGA: The power pack.
电源
VICTORIA: I'm looking!
我在找！
VICTORIA: Yes, yes, they look like the one. Yes, yes.
是的, 是的, 看起来就像这个, 是的
VARGA: You are coming with me, to the ice mountain.
你得跟我来, 到冰山去
VICTORIA: No, please.
不, 求你了
CLENT: Who are you?
你是谁？
VICTORIA: You killed him!
你杀了他！
VARGA: Come.
来
PENLEY: I er, I was going to give him this.
我, 呃, 我正打算把这个给他
DOCTOR: Oh, that's disgusting. It's just the thing. Did you do this?
哦, 这很难闻。正是这个。这是你干的吗？
PENLEY: I've come very close to it at times. I've never seen him look so peaceful.
事情发生的时候我离得不远, 我倒从来没见过他这么平和
DOCTOR: Oh, he'll be all right. Did you see who did do it?
哦, 他会没事的。你看到是谁干的了吗？
PENLEY: Yes. A monstrous looking creature. I didn't like the look of him at all.
是的, 一个怪物一样的家伙, 我一点也不喜欢他的样子
DOCTOR: Was there a girl there?
是不是还有一个女孩？
PENLEY: Yes, she seemed scared stiff.
是的, 她看来了吓坏了
DOCTOR: Well, why didn't you try and stop them?
那你怎么不试着阻止他们？
PENLEY: Well, I came here to get some drugs for a man who is sick. I couldn't run the risk of getting caught.
我来这里是拿点药, 有个人生病了。我可不能冒被抓走的风险
DOCTOR: But she's only a young girl!
但她只是一个小女孩儿！
PENLEY: She's alive. My friend will die if I don't get back.
她还活着, 但我不回去的话我的朋友就会死了
DOCTOR: Yes. Yes, I see.
行, 行, 我明白了
PENLEY: Are you going after them? I can take you part of the way.
你在追他们吗？我可以带你一段路
DOCTOR: No, no, they're searching already. There's a red alarm all over the base.
不, 他们已经在搜索了。整个基地拉了红色警报
PENLEY: Well, I've got what I want. I'm off.
我已经拿到了我想要的, 得走了
DOCTOR: Penley?
你是Penley？
PENLEY: You know about me then. My escapades in computer-land.
你知道我的情况, 我逃离电脑世界的故事
DOCTOR: They need you here, you know. They need you desperately.
这里他们需要你, 你看。他们非常需要你
PENLEY: Needing isn't getting. I'm free of their problems for good.
那也不代表他们能得到。能不被他们的问题烦绕, 我过得很好
DOCTOR: They're your problems too, you know. It's your world.
他们同时也是你的问题, 你知道的, 这也是你的世界
PENLEY: My world is up here. Private and no admittance. Well, I'm going to go then.
我的世界就在这里。自己自足, 也不欠别人什么。我得走了
DOCTOR: I expect you know what you're doing.
我期望你清楚你在干什么
PENLEY: You know it's nice to meet one that they haven't got at yet.
能遇到一个还没有被他们同化的人, 还真是不错啊 (FIXME)
DOCTOR: Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢你
PENLEY: Goodbye.
再见
DOCTOR: Goodbye.
GARRETT: They're in here.
他们在这里
DOCTOR: Where's Victoria?
Victoria 在哪里?
GARRETT: Leader Clent!
Clent队长
ARDEN: What's happened?
怎么了？
CLENT: Where are they?
这是什么？
GARRETT: I've just had a message from the perimeter gate. He smashed his way through, taking the girl with him.
我刚收到一条消息, 在防线边上, 他闯出去了, 还带着那个女孩儿
CLENT: He knocked me out with a power pack.
他用一个电源箱把我砸晕了
DOCTOR: With a power pack? You mean the one that you used to unfreeze him?
电源箱？你是说用来解冻他的那种？
CLENT: Yes. And he and the girl have many more.
是的, 他和那个女孩儿拿了一些
ARDEN: To revitalise others like himself.
要去复活他的同伴！
CLENT: Others? What do you mean. We don't know that there are others.
同伴？什么意思？ 我们不知道他还有其他同伴
JAMIE: Well now, he'll head for the glacier. Let's get way after him.
现在他已经往冰川那边去了, 我们去追他啊
DOCTOR: No. That's what he wants us to do. That's why he's taken Victoria with him as a hostage. No, we must let him show his hand first.
不, 他正如他所愿了。这也是他为什么要把 Victoria 带在身边作为人质。不, 我们必须得让他先亮出底牌
JAMIE: But we can't just stand around waiting?
但我们不能这里干站着等啊？
DOCTOR: We're not going to. Only until morning. That'll be time enough.
我们不会。只要等到早上。这样时间就够了
CLENT: No, now! Must I remind you of the mission that you have yet to accomplish?
不, 现在去！是不是还得我来提醒你, 你还有项任务要完成？
ARDEN: Oh no, Clent, not at night. Not for you or anybody. You've never been out there at night.
哦, 不要, Clent, 不要晚上去。你不要, 谁也不要。你从来没有晚上出去过
VARGA: I have located my warriors. When your friends come after us, they will find a surprise.
我已经定位出了我的勇士们。如果你的朋友们出来追我们, 他们会发现一个惊喜
VICTORIA: What are you going to do?
你打算干什么？
VARGA: You'll see. Don't try to run away.
你会明白了。别试着逃跑
VICTORIA: I was only going to watch you.
我只打算看看你
VARGA: You are going to help me.
你得帮助我
PENLEY: Twenty four hours and you'll be your old animal-like self again.
再过24小时你就又跟老动物一样了。FIXME
And while you're undergoing repairs, Storr, old chap, I'm going to do a bit of hunting myself, up on the glacier.
你在这里慢慢养着, Storr, 老伙计。我要要出去探查点情况, 到冰河那里去
Something strange is happening, Elric Penley, honoured sir.
总觉得有点不对劲, Elric Penley, 尊敬的先生
That warrior, that girl, that funny, scruffy looking chap. Something strange indeed.
那个寒冰勇士, 那个女孩儿, 还有那个好笑又邋遢的家伙。的确有点奇怪
Something disturbing. Something to do with the ice.
很困扰人, 还跟冰山有关
And if what that particular chap has said is true, if they really need me, it may mean the parting of the ways for us.
如果那个家伙说的是实情, 如果他们真的需要我, 这就意味着我们得做一个抉择了
VARGA: It's done. They are free. And now, to bring them back to life.
完成了。他们自由了。现在, 让他们复活!